When we're talking with friends or maybe in a more formal situation like a job interview we need to
当我们与朋友交谈时，或者在更正式的情况下（例如工作面试）时，我们需要
ask what other people are going to do what other people might do.
询问其他人会做什么其他人可能会做什么。
So let's just go over very quickly for common questions that we can use to ask about the future.
因此，让我们快速回顾一下我们可以用来询问未来的常见问题。
The first three are more casual and then the last one is a bit more formal.
前三个比较随意，最后一个比较正式。
OK so the first one.
好的，所以第一个。
What have you got going on today.
你今天有什么事。
Very common.
很常见。
You talk to your friend.
你和你的朋友说话。
It's morning maybe or it's early afternoon.
可能是早上，也可能是下午。
What have you got going on today.
你今天有什么事。
This is about the future.
这是关于未来的。
It means basically what are your plans today.
这基本上意味着你今天的计划。
Now you could say that we could say what are your plans today.
现在你可以说我们可以说你今天的计划是什么。
What are your plans this weekend.
这个周末你有什么计划。
What are your plans next week.
你下周有什么计划。
What are your plans for your vacation.
你的假期有什么计划。
What are your plans this afternoon.
你今天下午有什么打算。
This one is really useful because we can talk about any time but it's about the future.
这个真的很有用，因为我们可以谈论任何时间，但它是关于未来的。
But what have you got going on is usually going to be today or maybe this week very near term very near
但是你要发生的事情通常是今天或者本周可能非常接近非常接近
near term future.
近期的未来。
But it's pretty common.
但这很常见。
Do you have anything going on later.
以后有什么事吗。
This one is something we might use in the invitation situation.
这是我们可能在邀请情况下使用的东西。
We did the class about inviting right.
我们上了关于邀请权的课。
If we're going to invite someone.
如果我们要邀请某人。
Do you have anything going on later this is maybe when we're preparing to ask them if they want to do
你以后有什么事情吗？这可能是我们准备问他们是否愿意做的时候
something.
某物。
Probably we want to hang out or do something fun.
可能我们想出去玩或做一些有趣的事情。
What are your plans.
你的计划是什么。
Sometimes we can just say this by itself but usually it does have a time on it.
有时我们可以自己这么说，但通常它确实有时间。
So these are these three common very common casual pretty casual.
所以这就是这三种常见的很普通的休闲相当的休闲。
OK.
好的。
Where do you see yourself in three years now.
三年后你在哪里看到自己。
This is something that you would hear in a serious conversation with a friend about their life goals.
这是您在与朋友就他们的人生目标进行认真交谈时会听到的内容。
Right.
正确的。
OK.
好的。
So you're thinking about quitting your job.
所以你正在考虑辞职。
All right.
没问题。
Where do you see yourself in three years.
三年后你在哪里看到自己。
That means what do you imagine about yourself in three years.
这意味着你对三年后的自己的想象。
It's also a very very common job interview question.
这也是一个非常非常常见的求职面试问题。
They will often ask you where do you see yourself in five years.
他们经常会问你五年后你在哪里看到自己。
So then we can maybe explain something about our goals and if it's a job interview maybe that should
那么我们也许可以解释一下我们的目标，如果是工作面试，也许应该
be related to this job probably.
大概与这份工作有关。
We'll look at an example of how we can answer that question later in this lesson.
我们将在本课后面看一个如何回答这个问题的例子。